我们,是水晶
♪ We ♪ are the crystal
战士
♪ gems
我们总能拯救世界
♪ we'll always save the day
如果你认为我们不行
♪ and if you think we can't, ♪
我们总能找到方法
♪ we'll always find a way
这就是为什么这个世界
♪ that's why the people
的人
♪ of this world
相信
♪ believe in
石榴
♪ Garnet
紫晶
♪ Amethyst
和珍珠
♪ and Pearl
和史蒂文!
and Steven!
史蒂文的生日
欢迎关注微博@UUU字幕组，获取最新熟肉信息！
出品
presisco
翻译
零玖/presisco
校对
presisco
特效
压制
presisco
我不敢相信总算到我的生日了
I can't believe it's finally my birthday!
你们确定暂时放下钻头的工作没影响吧?
You're sure it's okay we're taking a break from the drill?
橄榄石会维持住进度的
Peridot will keep us on schedule.
呦,橄榄,你确定你不想参与进来吗?
Yo, peri, you sure you don't want to get in on this?
我们该庆祝我们的进度了
We should celebrate our progress.
我们也该庆祝你的进展了
We should celebrate your progress.
你今年长高了好多
You've grown a lot this year.
他当然啦
He certainly has.
对,没错,我觉得也是!
Yeah. Yeah, I guess so!
史蒂文!
Steven!
康妮!
Connie!
生日快乐!
Happy Birthday!
谢谢!欢迎来到派对
Thanks! Welcome to the party.
我能为您献上一杯,饮品,吗?
May I offer you a refreshment?
史蒂文从身后掏出两盒饮料的动作属于“hammerspace”的典型运用；
“hammerspace”指在动画，漫画与游戏中角色背上的“神秘维度”——总是能莫名其妙的掏出些东西
哦,史蒂文,真是个绅士啊
Oh, Steven, how gentile.
那么,这就是谷仓
So, this is the barn.
我很惊讶你家长
I'm surprised your parents
让你在这里度过周末
are letting you stay for the weekend.
这并不容易
It wasn't easy.
他们同意我来,只要我带着
They only let me come after equipping me
地球上的每一样安全设备
with every piece of safety gear on the planet.
我应该怎么用这个除颤器?
What should I do with this defibrillator?
呃,我们可以先将它留在车里
Um, we can just leave it in the car for now.
当然,我很高兴你能来
Well, I'm glad you could make it.
我也是
Me too.
好吧,让开点,康妮!
All right, move it, Connie!
明明是我先的
I was his best friend first.
生日快乐!
Happy Birthday!
好啦,小肉球
Okay, shtuball.
让我看看你
Let me get a look at you.
老爸!
Dad!
对不起,我只是不敢相信
Sorry, I just can't believe
我的小男孩长得如此之快
my little boy's growing up so quickly.
就好像昨天你还是个孩子,
Seems like just yesterday you were a baby,
而现在你已经14岁了
and now you're turning 14 years old.
史蒂文,你14了?!
Steven, you're 14?!
是啊?
Yeah?
但,我才只有12岁又四分之三!
But, I'm only 12 3/4!
你比我大?
You're older than me?
我-我简直无法相信!
I-I don't believe it!
其实,没错,看这个
Well, sure. Check it out.
让我们瞧瞧,我们有-
Let's see.We have --
新生儿
Infant
宝宝
Baby
幼童
Toddler
这叫什么-少年
what's it called -- adolescent.
少年,少年,少年
Adolescent, adolescent, adolescent.
喔,看来你在这里待得有点久啊,伙计
Whoa, looks like you stagnated there a little bit, buddy.
宇宙先生,我能向你展示一下除颤器如何使用吗?
Mr. Universe, could I show you how the defibrillator works?
哦,呃,当然
Oh, uh, sure.
马上就回来,小砸
Be right back, kiddo.
那么,他不会再长大了?
So, he's not going to grow up?
车内“ROCK”的海报与《动物之森》中的K.K.Slider类似
其实,这不好说
Well, it's hard to say.
他是个宝石人,而宝石人并不会真的长大的
He's a gem, and gems don't really grow up.
我是说,我从22岁起就认识了那些宝石人
I mean, I've known the gems since I was 22,
之后她们一直没变过
and they never change.
他们就是这样
They just are what they are.
但史蒂文不像其他宝石人-他一半是人类
But Steven's not like the other gems -- he's half human.
所以我并不真的确定他会如何成长
So I'm not really sure how he's gonna age.
我们只能走一步看一步了
We're just gonna have to wait and see.
那么,就这样吧
Yes, right.
你还好吗?
Are you okay?
很好,很好
Yeah, yeah.
人类一族?
Human beings?
人类一族
Human beings.
嘿,生日小子,在干哈?
Hey, birthday man, whatcha doin'?
我想挂上这个标语,所以-
I want to hang up this banner, so --
dude, it'd be easier if you just
streeeeeetch on up here.
UUU太空旅行
哈!怎么样?
Ha! How's that?
哦,对啊
Oh, yeah.
来呀,评价一下?
Come on, what's the verdict?
我不能一直这么撑着
I can't hold this forever.
呃,看起来不错?
Uh, looks great.
我的生日伙计在这!
There's my b-day guy!
呃,怎么了,老爸?
Uh, what's up, dad?
史蒂文生日快乐
我们马上就要开始了
We're almost ready to start.
我们也准备好你的生日袍和生日冠了
Got your birthday cape and crown ready, too.
给你,穿上然后在谷仓里等着
Here, put 'em on and go wait in the barn.
那么,现在坐好
Okay, now sit tight.
你会喜欢这个的
You're gonna love this.
好吧,史蒂文,我开门了!
Okay, Steven, open up!
惊-
Surpri--
喔
Wow.
我了个-
Oh, my.
呃?
Huh?
嗯,嗯,嗯
Hm, hm, hm.
史蒂文,你感觉还好吗?
Steven, are you feeling okay?
你看起来不错,史蒂文
You look good, Steven.
谢谢,石榴
Thanks, Garnet.
伙计,你脖子!
Dude, your neck!
怎么了?
What about it?
你居然有了!
You have one!
那么...你只是突然间长起来了?
So...You just grew all of a sudden?
我刚刚突然来了魔法蹿个而已
I had a magical growth spurt just now.
酷啊,对不对?
Cool, right?
哦,没错
Oh, right.
这非常酷!
It's totally cool!
既然如此,那么让派对嗨起来!
All right, then. Let's get this party started.
好!
Yeah!
来尝尝这个饼干猫蛋糕吧!
Let's eat this cookie cake!
给你,史蒂文
Here, Steven.
喔,谢谢
Wow, thanks.
噢,你不用解开它
Oh, you don't have to untie that.
这只是个盒子
It's just a box made to look
长得像是我花了功夫包装一样
like I spent a lot of time wrapping it.
哦哦哦,一件新衬衫!
Ohhh, a new shirt!
颜色不错嘛
What a pretty color.
穿上看看
Try it on.
哦,我猜尺寸不合适,既然...
Oh, I guess it doesn't fit since...
不,别担心-像这样就挺好的
No, don't worry -- it fits fine just like this.
球来啦!
Here it comes!
我能做到,珍珠!
I got it, Pearl!
不错嘛,康妮
Nice, Connie.
你打的你去捡
If you hit it, you get it.
别担心,我能够到!
No worries. I'll grab it!
康妮,让我来
Connie, let me.
哦,很棒啊,谢谢,史蒂文
Oh, cool. Thanks, Steven.
没问题,康妮
No problem, Connie.
呦,把那个羽毛球拿回来吧
Yo, bring back that shuttlecock!
哦,不!
Oh, no!
格雷格抽出的专辑封面与石榴的配音Estelle的“shine”类似，不过歌手名字改为了Stella
这首献给生日小子,
This one goes out to the birthday boy,
还有他最好的朋友
and his best friend.
我仍然不敢相信这么长时间来你一直比我要大
I still can't believe all this time you were older than me.
你应该偶尔偷偷带我去看PG-13的电影
You should sneak me into a pg-13 movie sometime.
哦,是啊
Oh, yeah.
不,我只是开个玩笑
No, I'm just kidding.
我绝对不会让你去犯法的
I would never ask you to break the law.
不过有趣的是我现在要抬起头看你了
It's funny that I have to look up at you now, though.
好的有趣还是坏的?
Funny good or f-funny bad?
好的
Funny good.
噢,史蒂文玩的很开心
Aw, Steven's having fun.
我们真是嗨趴能手啊
We know how to throw a party.
打扰一下,康妮
Excuse me for a moment, Connie.
我要去...整理一下
I'm gonna go... Freshen up.
马上就来
Be right back.
哦,天哪!
Oh, geez!
如果我能在剩下的日子里一直保持如此,
If I can just keep this up for the rest of my life,
没人就会怀疑-
no one will suspect a th--
你在干嘛?
What are you doing?
你们...
What are...
在做什么?
you doing?
你对你的身体做什么了?
What are you doing to your body?
喔喔喔,你白天一直在拉伸你自己吗?!
Whoa, whoa, whoa, have you been stretching yourself out all day?!
不,我只是...伸个懒腰
No, I was just... Slouching.
你为什么要这么做?
Why are you doing this?
这一点也不像你
It really isn't like you.
因为,爸爸,我不能永远只像个孩子
Because, dad, I can't stay a kid forever.
当康妮长大并成为总统后,
When Connie grows up and becomes president,
那会让我变成什么?第一正太吗?
what is that gonna make me, first boy?!
史蒂文,你不能一直维持拉伸的
Steven, you can't just keep stretching forever.
如果你坚持的时间过长,你会伤害到自己的
If you hold it too long, you could really hurt yourself.
算了吧,其实,我是半人
Yeah, well, I'm half human,
所以也许我就不是这样的
so maybe it works different for me.
我们只能走一步看一步,对不对
We'll just have to wait and see, right?
史蒂文...
Steven...
那个是...直升犬属星座
That one's canis helicopterus.
呃,呃,直升星座?
Uh, uh, helicopterus?
没错,狗升机!猜到了吗?
Yeah, dogcopter! Get it?
现在你想一个
Now you make one up.
嗯...好吧,呃...
Mm...Okay, um...
那个是,呃...蛇星座
That one's, uh...Snake constellation.
那还...好吧
That's pretty good.
你舒服吗?
Are you okay?
看起来你好像要吐
It looks like you're gonna throw up.
哦,还好,一切正常
Oh, yeah. E-everything's fine.
好吧,那不错
Okay, that's good.
你得知道,说实话,我-我之前还有点担心
You know, to be honest, I-I was a little worried before.
这听起来很蠢,
This might sound silly,
但我很高兴我能陪你一起长大
but I'm really glad that I'm going to get to grow up with you.
史蒂文?
Steven?
史蒂文,到底怎么了?发生了什么?
Steven, what's going on? What happened?
什么?
What?
我们刚才只是在聊天,然后突然间-
We were just talking, then all of a sudden --
他变回婴儿了?
he turned back into a baby?!
对!
Yes!
伙计,我怎么说的!
Dude, I told you!
将你的身体拉伸这么长时间对你没好处
Stretching your body out for that long is not good for you.
给你啦,珍珠
Here you go, Pearl.
哦,不,不,不要把他给我
Oh, no, no, don't give him to me.
把他给我吧,紫晶
Hand him over, Amethyst.
接住了
Here you go.
我的能力对新生儿毫无作用
My power means nothing to an infant.
好吧,这个归我管吧
Okay, this is my department.
你打算怎么做?
What are you gonna do?
别担心,我能行的
Don't worry, I got this.
宝石人们怎么会不知所措呢?
How can the gems not know what to do?
你以为她们了解如何抚养一个宝宝?
You think they knew the first thing about raising a baby?
其实一直都是我,但我不知道为什么
That was all me, but I don't get it.
开车原来总能让他安静下来
Driving always used to calm him down.
但我们该怎么让他变回去?!
But how do we change him back?!
我不知道,听着,康妮,让我带你回家吧
I don't know. Look, Connie, let me take you home.
我-我会在这一切都解决后给你回电话的
I-I'll call you when this all gets sorted out.
等等,不
W-wait, no.
我要留下来
I want to stay.
你确定?
Are you sure?
没错
Yeah.
我只想在史蒂文身边
I just want to be there for Steven.
别担心,史蒂文
Don't worry, Steven.
不论你多大对我都无所谓
It doesn't matter to me what age it seems like you are.
我只是想和你在一起而已
I want to hang out with you no matter what.
你爸爸仍然得运营他的洗车房,
Your dad still has to run his car wash,
而宝石人们得去做她们的事,
and the gems have to do gem stuff,
那么我会在他们没空时陪你的
so I'll watch you when they're not around.
我也可以在与珍珠完成训练后来看你的!
I can come see you after I'm done training with Pearl, too!
那听起来有趣吧?
Doesn't that sound fun?
看看啊-他总算不哭了
Look at that -- he finally stopped crying.
总之,这是个好的开始
Well, that's a start.
怎么了,紫晶?
What's up, Amethyst?
史蒂文宝宝该换尿布了
Baby Steven needs changing.
哦,我的天,哦哦哦,我的天!
Oh, my gosh. Ohhh, my gosh!
他变得更小了?史蒂文变成微观物了!
Did he get even smaller? Steven's microscopic!
他变回受精卵了!
He's reverted back to a zygote!
所有人!史蒂文变成-
Everyone, Steven is --
快看,现在合身了
Look, it fits now.
你又变回正常了!
You're back to normal!
真对不起那变成了一场灾难
Sorry this was a disaster.
我只想为你变得成熟一点
I wanted to look older for you.
那无所谓
That doesn't matter.
我听到你在面包车里说的话了
I heard what you said in the van.
如果我不能像人类一样成长的话真的没问题吗?
It's really okay if I don't age like a human?
当然啦!
Of course it is!
我就是喜欢你这样啊
I like you just the way you are.
哦,好吧!
Oh, okay!
呃,史蒂文,你下巴上有东西
Uh, Steven, you've got something on your cheek.
呃?
Huh?
是胡子啊!
Its a facial hair!
真的?
Really?
爸爸!
Dad!
是什么,史蒂文?
What is it, little man?
看这个!
Look at this!
我的妈,你长胡子了!
Holy smokes, you're growing a beard!
你真的在长大!
You really are getting older!
大家快看这个!
Everybody, look at this!
难以置信
Unbelievable.
非常有趣
Very impressive.
那里还会长出更多的吗?
Is there more where that came from?